// Login //

window.addEventListener("load", function () {

  const localStrorageName = JSON.parse(localStorage.getItem("username"))
  console.log(window.location.pathname)
  if (!localStrorageName && window.location.pathname === '/quiz.html') {
    window.location.replace('index.html')
  }

})


function quit() {
  localStorage.removeItem("username")
  window.location = 'index.html'
}

function myfunction() {
  var x = document.getElementById("pass");

  if (x.type === "password") {
    x.type = "text";
  } else {
    x.type = "password";
  }
}

function validate() {
  var username = document.getElementById("username")
  if (username.value.trim() != "") {
    alert("Login Successful");
    localStorage.setItem("username", JSON.stringify(username.value))
    window.location.replace("quiz.html");
    return false;
  } else {
    alert("Login Failed, please enter username longer than 5 char");
  }
}

// Quiz Question //

const Data = [{
    question: "Which one of these rules are allowed in Kickboxing?",
    a: "Kicks above the elbow",
    b: "Throwing punching in chest",
    c: "Sweeping opponent to the ground",
    d: "Kicks below the waist",
    correct: "d",


  },

  {

    question: "Where did Kickboxing originate from?",
    a: "America",
    b: "Germany",
    c: "Australia",
    d: "Southeast Asia",
    correct: "d",

  },

  {
    question: "Which one is the benefit of Kickboxing?",
    a: "More sleep",
    b: "Hydration",
    c: "Self-Defense",
    d: "All of the above",
    correct: "c",


  },

  {
    question: "Which of these is not a Kickboxing style?",
    a: "Muay Thai",
    b: "Firestarter",
    c: "Full Contact Karate",
    d: "Savate",
    correct: "b",

  },

  {
    question: "Which country does Muay Thai orginates from?",
    a: "Japan",
    b: "China",
    c: "Thailand",
    d: "South Korea",
    correct: "c",
  },

  {
    question: "Who is the 2022 Heavyweight UFC Champion?",
    a: "Francis Ngannou",
    b: "Yoel Romero",
    c: "Colby Covington",
    d: "Kamaro Usman",
    correct: "a",


  },

  {
    question: "How many divisions are in the UFC?",
    a: "8",
    b: "15",
    c: "11",
    d: "12",
    correct: "d",


  },

  {
    question: "When year was the UFC founded?",
    a: "1993",
    b: "1972",
    c: "1985",
    d: "1991",
    correct: "a",

  },

  {
    question: "Which one is considered a mixed martial arts (MMA)?",
    a: "Taekwondo",
    b: "Karate",
    c: "Hybrid combat sport",
    d: "Judo",
    correct: "c",

  },

  {
    question: "Which is the main category of Martial arts?",
    a: "Japanese",
    b: "Chinese",
    c: "Korean",
    d: "All of the above",
    correct: "d",

  },

]


function increaseProgressBar (incVal) {
     const myBar = document.getElementById("myBar")
     const questionCount = document.getElementById("question-count");

     const questionCounter = parseInt(questionCount.innerText)
     const maxQuestions = Data.length

      myBar.style.width = `${(questionCounter/maxQuestions) * 100}%`;
  
}





 // Sourced code from a youtuber (CodeWithDarkwa) //
const grabId = (idName) => {

  const ElementId = document.getElementById(idName);
  console.log(ElementId, "<==idname")
  if (ElementId) return ElementId;
  // throw new Error(`cannot find the id ${idName}`);

};
const option1 = grabId("option1");
const option2 = grabId("option2");
const option3 = grabId("option3");
const option4 = grabId("option4");
let nextBtn = grabId("btn-next");
let prevBtn = grabId("btn-prev");
const quiz = grabId("quiz");
const question = document.querySelector("h3");
const answers = document.querySelectorAll(".answer");

let currentQuize = 0;
let score = 0;

loadQuize();

function loadQuize() {

  unCheckAnswer();
  let nextOption = Data[currentQuize];
  console.log(nextOption, "next")
  question.innerText = nextOption.question;
  option1.innerText = nextOption.a;
  option2.innerText = nextOption.b;
  option3.innerText = nextOption.c;
  option4.innerText = nextOption.d;
  nextBtn.addEventListener("click", nextQuestion);
  prevBtn.addEventListener("click", PreviousQuestion);
}

function nextQuestion() {
  const answer = getValue();
  console.log(quiz, "<===quiZ")
  const questionCount = document.getElementById("question-count");
  questionCount.innerText = parseInt(questionCount.innerText) + 1
  if (answer) {
    if (answer === Data[currentQuize].correct) {
      score++;
    }
    currentQuize++;
    if (currentQuize < Data.length) {
      loadQuize();
    } else if (score === Data.length) {
      console.log("you reached")
      quiz.innerHTML = `
        <h1> Congratulations üòç <br/>You scored ${score}/${Data.length}</h1> 
        `;
    } else {
      quiz.innerHTML = `<h1> üòì You scored ${score}/${Data.length}
       
        `;
    }
  }
  increaseProgressBar(10)
}


function PreviousQuestion() {
  if (currentQuize.valueOf() === 0) {
    alert("Can't go back anymore");
  } else {
    loadQuize();
  }
}

function getValue() {
  let value = undefined;
  answers.forEach((answer) => {
    if (answer.checked) {
      value = answer.id;
    }
  });
  return value;
}

function unCheckAnswer() {
  answers.forEach((answer) => {
    answer.checked = false;
  });
}